welltrainedmind.com 2017-02-17

# Privacy Policy - Well-Trained Mind

Welcome to [welltrainedmind.com](https://welltrainedmind.com/) _._ Here you can buy books and curricula written by Susan Wise Bauer, author of The Well-Trained Mind, and others. This site (the “WTM _Site_ ”) is owned by Well-Trained Mind Press (“ _WTM_ ” or “ _we_ ”). This privacy policy explains our practices regarding collection, use, and disclosure of personally identifying information that you may provide to us through the WTM Site.

  1. **What kinds of personally identifying information do we collect on the WTM Site?**
    * When you register, we ask you for your e-mail address, first and last name, company name (if applicable), street address and phone number, and your credit-card information.
    * When you subscribe to our newsletter, we ask you for your name and e-mail address.
    * If you buy something as a guest (without having registered), we will ask you for your e-mail address, first and last name, company name (if applicable), street address and phone number, and your credit-card information.
    * If you buy something and ask that it be shipped to someone else, we will ask you for that person’s name and street address and phone number.
    * If you sign up for our affiliate program, we will ask you for your e-mail address, company name, a “checks payable to” name (which may be your first and last name), your tax identification number, first and last name, street address, fax number, and the number of your PayPal account if you have one.
    * If you want to contact us about the affiliate program, we ask you for your name and e-mail address.
  2. **How do we use the personally identifying information that we collect on the WTM Site?**
    * The personally identifying information that is provided on your registration form is entered into our Store database.
    * We forward your credit-card and billing information to our credit-card processor. We do not store any credit-card information on our servers.
    * We use your name and shipping address to ship anything you buy to you through one of our third-party shipping partners. The shipper will use your phone number and e-mail address to contact you if there is a problem with the shipment.
    * If you buy a product and ask that it be shipped to someone else, we use that person’s name and shipping address to send the product to that person through our third-party shipping partners. The shipper will use the person’s phone number and e-mail address to contact the person if there is a problem with the shipment.
    * We use the personally identifying information you enter on the newsletter subscription form to send you our newsletter. If you are a customer, we store your e-mail address on our servers and also share it with our e-blast provider, who sends out the newsletter. If you are not a customer and you ask to receive our newsletter, we will only forward your e-mail address to our third-party e-blast provider and not store it on our servers.
    * We use the personally identifying information you enter on the affiliate form to send you affiliate banners and text links and to send you any commissions you earn.
  3. **With whom do we share the personally identifying information that we collect on the WTM Site?**
    * As noted above: 
      * We share credit-card information with our outside credit-card provider.
      * We share with our third-party shippers all information provided on purchase forms, including names, addresses, phone numbers and e-mail addresses.
      * We share e-mail addresses with our third-party e-blast provider, who sends out our newsletter on our behalf to people who have signed up for it.
    * We do not share any of your personally identifying information with our affiliates. We only tell an affiliate when a sale has occurred on which that affiliate is entitled to a commission and the amount of that commission.
    * If WTM assigns or otherwise transfers the operations of the WTM Site that relates to your personally identifying information, WTM will transfer your personally identifying information to the successor entity.
    * If WTM is required to disclose your personally identifying information by any applicable law, court order, or government regulation, that company will comply with such law, court order, or regulation.
    * If you are a California resident, and you want to find out the names of any information brokers or any other third parties with whom we share your personally identifying information under California Privacy (Cal. Bus. & Prof. Code § 22575 et seq. (“ _Cal-OPPA_ ”)), send a request to: Well-Trained Mind Press  
Marketing Dep’t  
18021 The Glebe Lane  
Charles City, VA 23030Within thirty (30) days, we will provide you with that information.
  4. **What other kinds of identifying information are collected when you use the WTM Site?** **General**
    * The WTM Site also automatically collects aggregated information, demographic information and any other information that does not reveal your specific identity but that relates to your use of the WTM Site.  This kind of information is “passively” collected from you through browser navigational tools, such as cookies and pixel tags.  These types of technologies enable the WTM Site to compile statistics about our daily number of site visitors or specific page requests, while not identifying you personally, other than by your IP address, which is the Internet Protocol address of the computer that you use to access the Site.

**Cookies**

    * A cookie is a small data file that a Web site transfers to a user’s hard drive when a user visits the Web site.  A cookie file can contain information such as a unique ID that the site uses to track the pages visited, and is a standard method of registering website user preferences.  These preferences are stored in a file on your computer’s hard disk drive.
    * Cookies make it easier for you to use the WTM Site by enabling you to access your information when you “sign in” to your account, to make purchases and move uninterrupted between site areas.
    * We use “analytical” cookies to recognize and count the number of visitors to the WTM Site and to see how visitors move around the WTM Site when they’re using it. Cookies also allow us to provide you with customized content, keep track of preferences you specify while visiting the WTM Site, conduct general analysis and research, and identify purchases that you make in response to our advertising. This helps us improve the way the WTM Site works, for example by making sure users find what they need easily.
    * You can set your browser to accept all cookies, to reject cookies, or to notify you whenever a cookie is offered so that you can decide each time whether to accept it.  Rejecting a cookie, however, may preclude you from using, or may negatively affect the display or function of, the WTM Site or certain areas or features of the WTM Site. To learn more about cookies, including how to enable cookies, change your browser settings and find and delete cookies on your hard drive, please refer to your web browser’s help menus or visit [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

**Web beacons**

    * We may also use an application known as a “web beacon.” A web beacon is an electronic file that usually consists of a single-pixel image. It can be placed on a web page or in an email to transmit information, which could include personal information.  We use a web beacon for Facebook® that allows us to advertise on Facebook to people who have visited the WTM Site. If you are on the WTM Site when the Facebook web beacon is running, and then we run a “like” campaign on Facebook when you are on Facebook, you will see a “Like us” ad for Well-Trained Mind Press.  We also may use web beacons to assist in tracking and analyzing advertising effectiveness, verify purchases made on the WTM Site, count and recognize site visitors, and personalize your experience.
  5. **Can any third party track your use of the WTM Site?**
    * We use Google® Analytics.  Google tracks where you go on the WTM Site and combines that information with information that Google may have about you through your Google account (if you have one) and/or through your use of other Web sites that use Google Analytics.  Google and its affiliates may use cookies to serve advertisements about goods and services of interest to you on the WTM Site and on other sites that you visit.
    * If you do not want your data collected with Google Analytics, you can install the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on. This add-on instructs the Google Analytics JavaScript (ga.js, analytics.js, and dc.js) running on websites to prohibit sending information to Google Analytics. To opt out of Google Analytics, visit the [Google Analytics opt-out page](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout) and install the add-on for your browser. For more details on installing and uninstalling the add-on, please see the relevant help resources for your specific browser. Updates to your browser or operating system may affect the functionality of the opt-out add-on. You can learn about managing add-ons for Chrome [here](https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/142064). If you are not using Chrome, check directly with the manufacturer of your browser to determine whether add-ons will function properly on the browser version that you are using.
    * If you visit the WTM Site from or through a third-party site, such as a shopping comparison site or a site that carries an ad for the WTM Site, that site may monitor your visit to the WTM Site. We suggest you review the privacy and security policies of any site you are on so that you know whether this may happen.
    * With some browsers, it is possible for a user to activate a “Do Not Track” signal, to indicate that the user does not want to be tracked across the Web sites that the user visits. The WTM Site does not respond to Do Not Track signals. In other words, if you have activated a Do Not Track signal in your own browser, the WTM Site will not take any action to block tracking by Google or its affiliates of your activity on the WTM Site.
  6. **How can you manage your personally identifying information on the WTM Site?**
    * To keep your personally identifying information accurate, current, and complete, you can log in to your own account, or you can  contact: Well-Trained Mind Press  
Marketing Dep’t  
18021 The Glebe Lane  
Charles City, VA 23030
  7. **How do we protect and maintain the integrity of your personally identifying information on the WTM Site?**
    * We use SSL certificates to protect your personal information as you transmit it from your computer to the WTM Site and to protect your information from loss, misuse, and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, or destruction. We also use a software program to stop certain kinds of attacks. But no Internet transmission is ever 100% secure or error-free. In particular, e-mail sent to or from the WTM Site may not be secure. Be careful about sending us any confidential information, and keep secure any passwords, ID numbers, or other special access features that you use on the WTM Site.
    * We will retain your personally identifying information for the period necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this privacy policy or our data retention policies unless a longer retention period is required by law.
    * The WTM Site may contain links or references to other sites in addition to the ones we have already mentioned. Please be aware that _we do not control such other sites_ and that, in any case, _this privacy policy does not apply to those sites_. We encourage you to read the privacy policy of every site you visit.
  8. **How will you know if this policy has changed?**
    * If this privacy policy changes, the revised policy will be posted here.  Please check back periodically, and especially before you provide any personally identifying information.
    * This privacy policy was last updated on August 8, 2016.
